(沖田)わかりやしたか？
Smoking increases a person's risk of
developing pulmonary emphysema.
In addition, smoking by minors
is forbidden because it leads to severe
health issues and nicotine addiction.
Never smoke, even if asked to by others.
...Do you understand?
[Inhale, puff puff... Inhale, puff puff...]
[Hijikata-san, too much smoking is bad for your health.]
10 votes in favor, versus 1 against.
(沖田)賛成10人｡ 反対１人｡
(沖田)土方さん以外
全員 賛成ってことで➡
Everyone except Hijikata-san voted
in favor, so this bill is approved.
この議案は 可決されました｡
(沖田)真選組屯所は➡
The Shinsengumi headquarters
今日から 全域にわたり
禁煙にします｡
will no longer allow smoking
in all areas starting today.
(土方)おい…！
全域は やりすぎだろう｡
H-Hey, the whole headquarters
is going too far.
まるで 喫煙者を➡
It's like you're purposely keeping
smokers out of here.
締め出さんばかりの
勢いじゃねえか｡
At least make arrangements for
a designated smoking area.
せめて 喫煙所を設けるくらい
配慮が あっても…｡
なに 言ってんですか？ 土方さん｡
What are you saying, Hijikata-san?
ﾀﾊﾞｺなんて 百害あって 一利なし｡
Smoking is worse than athlete's foot.
法律で
禁止されてないってだけで➡
Even though it's not prohibited by
law, nicotine is actually a drug.
実情は ﾔｸですぜ｡ ﾔｸ｡
A drug!
(沖田)毎日 毎日 吸って吐いて
吸って吐いて 依存症でさぁ｡
Everyday, you inhale and
exhale, inhale and exhale,
you become addicted.
だから なんだっつんだ？
So, what's wrong with that?
Even if this is a personal matter for you,
(沖田)自分のことだからって➡
you can't run with this line of argument.
論法で 逃げようたって
いけやせんぜ｡
Anyone near a smoker is forced to
become second-hand smokers.
(沖田)喫煙者の
周りにいる人間は➡
無理やり 受動喫煙を
させられてるわけですからね…｡
But... But...
(土方)だけど… しかし…｡
(沖田)曲がりなりにも
真選組副長って 身の上だ｡
You're Vice-Chief of the Shinsengumi.
(沖田)周りのことも
考えてくだせえ｡
Please think about the other
people around you.
If a Vice-Chief can't even quit smoking
or halt a nicotine addition,
(沖田)副長が 禁煙も できねえ
ﾆｺ中状態ってことは➡
市民を取り締まる 真選組として
示しが つきやせん｡
it sets a bad example for everyone else.
な… なぁ 原田｡
H-Hey, Harada. You sometimes
smoke, don't you?
お前も たまには吸うよな？
いいのか？ 禁煙で…｡
Are you all right with this smoking ban?
(原田)いえ… ｵﾚは もう
完璧に やめたんで 関係ないっす｡
Yeah...I completely quit smoking,
so it doesn't matter to me.
(隊士の 咳き込む声)
It's already been decided.
とにかく…
もう 決まったことなんで…｡
(隊士)いや～
沖田さんの議題にしては➡
Man, even with Okita-san's proposal,
that was a productive meeting.
久しぶりに
有意義な会議に なったな～！
(隊士)あぁ｡
喫煙者なんつっても➡
Yeah. Speaking of smokers,
Vice-Chief was the only one.
もう 副長しか いなかったしな～｡
(原田)結構 煙たくて
迷惑してたんだよ｡
It was so smoky and awful in there.
(原田)服とか 臭くなってさ～｡
My clothes are covered in
that stinky smoke odor.
(隊士)やっぱ
武道を たしなむ者として➡
Any person who practices a martial
art knows smoking is unhealthy.
ﾀﾊﾞｺは いかんでしょ｡ ﾀﾊﾞｺは｡
["Within Each Box of Cigarettes, Are One or Two
Cigarettes That Smell Like Horse Dung"]
(土方)あの野郎…
ふざけやがって！
...gimme a break.
Is he seriously intending to keep
me out of the Shinsengumi?
(土方)ｵﾚを 本気で
真選組から 締め出すつもりか｡
(土方)ｸｿｯ！
Damn it. I might as well inhale as much
nicotine as possible while I'm outside.
(土方)外回りのうちに できるだけ
ﾆｺﾁﾝを摂取しておこう｡
んっ？
♪♪～
[Smoking on the street is prohibited.]
[BATTLE ROYAL HOST]
あっ… すいません｡
灰皿 あります？
Ah, excuse me.
Do you have an ashtray?
I'm sorry. This restaurant prohibits
smoking in the whole facility.
(店員)申し訳ありません｡
当店は
全席 禁煙と なっておりま～す！
♪♪～
どうなってんだ？ この街は…｡
What's with this city?
どこも かしこも
禁煙 禁煙 禁煙…｡
Signs everywhere say "No
Smoking," "No Smoking."
I'm sorry, but smoking
isn't allowed in here.
(店員)すいやせ～ん！
こちらでの喫煙は➡
ご遠慮いただいております｡
(おばちゃん)
ちょっと～！ ﾀﾊﾞｺ～!!
Hey! Your cigarette!
Cigarettes are...
(店員)ﾀﾊﾞｺは ちょっと…｡
♪♪～
Oh, no! What's he doing?!
(女)やだ～ なに？ あれ～｡
(女)見ちゃ ﾀﾞﾒ！
Don't stare.
け… 煙を 吸わせろ～!!
Let me smoke!
(土方)ううっ… ﾁｸｼｮｳ！
Damn it.
(土方)いつのまにか
ｵﾚたち 喫煙者の居場所が➡
I didn't even notice but
now I can see there's
どこにも
なくなってるじゃねえか！
no places for us smokers to go anymore.
｢吸うな｣と 言われると
よけいに 吸いたくなる…｡
I want to smoke even more
when I'm told not to.
もう ﾀﾞﾒだ…｡ もう 限界だ…｡
It's hopeless. I can't stand it anymore.
In this situation... I... I...
このままでは ｵﾚは… ｵﾚは…｡
(土方)あっ…！
[SMOKING AREA]
(土方)あれは…！
That's it!
見つけた！
ついに 見つけた… ｵｱｼｽ！
I found it! I finally found an oasis!
(草野ｱﾅ)続いてのﾆｭｰｽです｡
Here's our next story.
The universal environment
conservation meeting
全宇宙の 環境問題について
話し合われる➡
宇宙環境保全会議を
１週間後に控え➡
will be held one week from today.
これを機に 国民 一人ひとりが
真剣に考える機会を 設けようと➡
It'll talk about environment-related
issues in the whole universe.
幕府は本日より １週間にわたり➡
And the Bakufu is taking this opportunity
to ask the nation to start thinking about
ﾏｲｸﾛ環境保護ｷｬﾝﾍﾟｰﾝを 行うことを
発表しました｡
the environment as it launches the micro-environmental
protection campaign for one week from today.
(松平)ｵｿﾞﾝ層破壊とか
地球温暖化とかよう➡
Let's put aside the big problems of ozone
depletion and global warming.
まぁ そういう
でか～い課題は 置いといて➡
人間っつうのは
まず 目先の小さいことから➡
It's important for each person
to do their own part,
自分の やれることを
やっていくことが 大切なんだよ｡
no matter how small, to
help the environment.
All your small efforts will start to pile up
into one big push to save the earth.
そういう 小さいことは
積もり積もって➡
やがては 地球を救う
大きな力と なるわけよ｡ うん｡
Yeah, right...
おじさんが 言いたいのはね➡
What this old man is trying to say is, before
you go saving the huge Earth...
地球なんて
でかいもんを 救う前に➡
まず 自分というね➡
...you should first save yourself.
小さな存在を 救ってみろという➡
Someone who can't even save himself
won't be able to save the earth.
ﾃﾒｴも 救えねえﾔﾂに➡
地球なんて
救えるわきゃねえんだよ｡
Someone who can't even save himself
and is disliked by his daughter...
娘に 嫌われてる自分を
救えんようでは➡
地球は 救えねえんだよ｡
...won't be able to save the earth.
まっ ということで
今日から １週間➡
Well, we'll explore all of
that a week from today.
江戸全域にわたって
禁煙令を 施行します！
All of Edo...
...will assist in helping implement
the smoking ban.
(爆発音と 悲鳴)
(草野ｱﾅ)繰り返し お伝えします｡
We repeat.
Currently, an emergency smoking ban
is in effect throughout all of Edo.
(草野ｱﾅ)現在 江戸全域に➡
緊急戒厳禁煙令が
出されています｡
Smokers are asked to please throw
away all cigarettes immediately.
(草野ｱﾅ)喫煙者の方は 速やかに
お持ちのﾀﾊﾞｺを 捨ててください｡
ﾀﾊﾞ… ｺ…｡
(草野ｱﾅ)それ以外の方も➡
Ci...Ciga...rette...
Also, please never approach cigarette
vending machines or smoking areas.
ﾀﾊﾞｺの自販機 喫煙所には
決して 近寄らないでください｡
It'll lead to sever punishment.
We repeat...
(草野ｱﾅ)処罰の対象となります｡
繰り返し お伝えします｡
Are you taking a trip through
the universe, too?
(客)お宅も 宇宙旅行？
Man, times are sure changing.
いや～
すごい時代に なったもんだね～｡
まさか 星々を 股にかけて
旅行できる日が 来るなんてさ｡
I never thought we'd see the day when
we could travel between planets.
で… お宅は どこの星に行くの？
So, which planet are you going to?
(土方)…ﾊﾒｯｸ星｡
ﾊﾒｯｸ星？
Planet Hamek.
[Note: Parody of Planet Namek from Dragon Ball.]
Planet Hamek? There's nothing
to see in that countryside.
あんな田舎 何も 見るとこないよ｡
ﾀﾊﾞｺ畑しか ねえし｡
It's nothing but tobacco fields.
Why are you going there?
何しに行くの？
決まってんだろ…｡
...Naturally...
ﾀﾊﾞｺを 吸いにいくんだよ！
...to smoke some cigarettes!
ひぃ～っ！
喫煙者 なめんじゃねえぞ…｡
Don't underestimate a smoker.
こっちはな 単行本の表紙で➡
They claimed the cigarette was edited
out of the manga cover because
[Note: Cigarette images were removed from
GinTama manga vol.8 and vol.16 covers.]
｢高校生が ﾀﾊﾞｺを吸ってるように
見えます｣とか…｡
I looked like a high
school student smoking.
They also said it was never a good
idea to show smokers on the cover.
そもそも 表紙で
｢喫煙は まずいです｣とか➡
わけの わからん ｲﾁｬﾓﾝつけられて
ﾀﾊﾞｺ ｶｯﾄされたりな｡
And they ended up not using
someone smoking.
｢これは ﾎﾟｯﾁｰです｣的な感じで
ごまかしたり➡
And we deceptively said it was a pocky chocolate
snack when it was really a cigarette,
北米での ｺﾞｰﾙﾃﾞﾝﾀｲﾑ
放映 あきらめたり➡
or else we'd be forced to give up airing the
show in prime time in North America,
Ｒ指定だって 甘んじて受ける
覚悟だったりな～！
or be stuck with an R rating.
And yet I still haven't given up smoking!
それでも やめずに
吸い続けてきたんだよ ｵﾒｴ！
Once the smoking ban starts,
I'll smoke outside Earth!
(土方)禁煙令が 出されたんなら
地球の外で 吸ってやる！
(土方)ﾀﾊﾞｺが なくなったら
原産地にまで 取りにいってやる！
If cigarettes run out, I'll even
travel to their place of origin!
(土方)喫煙者
なめんじゃねえぞ～!!
Don't underestimate a smoker!
(長老)そうかい そうかい！
I see, I see.
こんな遠くまで
我が ﾊﾒｯｸ星のﾀﾊﾞｺを➡
I'm so glad to hear that
you came all the way to
お吸いに なられに
来なさったとは…｡
Planet Hamek to smoke our cigarettes.
嬉しい限りです｡
しかし 残念ながら➡
Unfortunately, this planet
has been turned into
この星は
悪の帝王… ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞの手によって➡
a scorched field by the evil
emperor, Breeza.
[Note: Parody of Frieza from Dragon Ball.]
焼け野原に
変えられてしまいましてね…｡
So cigarettes are no longer...
ﾀﾊﾞｺは もう…｡
♪♪～
これが 最後の１本なのです｡
This is the last one.
♪♪～
よいですか！ １本だけで…！
Is that all right? Just one...?
(長老)あぁっ…！
(ﾃﾞﾙﾃﾞ)やめろよ じいちゃん！
Stop it, Grandpa!
これ ﾃﾞﾙﾃﾞ！ 離しなさい…！
Hey, Delde! Take your hands off me!
[Note: Parody of Dende from Dragon Ball.]
それは！
父ちゃんが作った 最後のﾀﾊﾞｺ!!
That's...! That's the last
cigarette my dad made!
ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞに殺された
父ちゃんの形見じゃないか!!
It's a memento of my dad,
who was killed by Breeza.
♪♪～
((ﾃﾞﾙﾃﾞ:父ちゃん！ 父ちゃ～ん！
Dad! Dad!
(ﾃﾞﾙﾃﾞ)父ちゃ～ん!!
Dad!
♪♪～
(父)ﾃﾞﾙﾃﾞ～！
Delde!
♪♪～
(爆発音)
と… 父ちゃん…｡
...Da...Dad...
♪♪～
はぁぁぁぁ～っ…!!
あっ！ 父ちゃん!!
Da...! Dad!
父ちゃ～ん!!
Dad!
♪♪～
父ちゃ～ん!!))
Dad...
と… 父ちゃんの…｡
Da... Dad's...
(長老)黙らんか ﾃﾞﾙﾃﾞ！
Shut up, Delde!
(長老)ﾀﾊﾞｺというのは
吸うために 存在するのだ！
Cigarettes exist to be smoked.
Cigarettes that you can't smoke shouldn't
even be called cigarettes at all!
(長老)吸えないﾀﾊﾞｺなど
ﾀﾊﾞｺではない!!
What do you think would please
your father the most?
ﾀﾝｽの中で ただ 湿気ていくのと
おいしく吸ってもらうのと➡
To let the cigarette get moist in a
drawer or let someone smoke it?
ｱｲﾂは どちらを喜ぶと思う！
♪♪～
と… 父ちゃんのﾀﾊﾞｺ…➡
Da...Dad's cigarette...
味わって 吸ってください…｡
...please enjoy smoking it...
♪♪～
(いびき)
あれ？ 奇遇ですね
ﾊﾊ… あの… ﾀﾊﾞｺ吸えました？
Oh! What a coincidence!
Well, were you able to smoke?
Are you on your way home?
帰り道ですか？
(土方)ちげえよ｡
No.
えっ どこに行くんですか？
What? Where are you going then?
ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞ 倒しに行くんだよ｡
I'm going to defeat Breeza!
Huh? Breeza? What? Aren't
you going there to smoke?
(客)えっ ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞ？
ﾀﾊﾞｺ吸いに
来たんじゃないんですか？
There's no way I can smoke
something like that!
(土方)
吸えるわけねえだろ あんなもん！
(客)えっ!?
(土方)ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞ ぶっ殺して➡
What?!
I'll kill Breeza and smoke afterwards!
その後 吸うんだよ！
ｱｲﾂ 絶対 ﾀﾊﾞｺ持ってるんだよ｡
He definitely has cigarettes.
次は絶対 吸ってやるよ ﾁｸｼｮｳ！
Next time, I'll definitely smoke
cigarettes, damn it!
(ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞ)ｸｸｸ… よもや
この私に 挑んでこようとは…｡
I never suspected that
you were against me.
But I admire your rashness.
その無謀さだけは評価しましょう｡
♪♪～
＜ｶﾞﾒ仙人:真撰組の禁煙令に
端を発した➡
Hijikata's quest to smoke
a single cigarette started
[Note: A parody of Master Roshi's
narrations from Dragon Ball.]
土方の 一服のﾀﾊﾞｺを求める旅は
苦難を極め…＞
because of the Shinsengumi's
smoking ban.
The trip has been full of hardships.
((まぁ ということで
今日から１週間➡
Well, we'll explore all of
that a week from today.
江戸全域にわたって
禁煙令を施行します))
All of Edo will assist in helping
implement the smoking ban.
＜ その旅路は いよいよ
宇宙へと向かった＞
But finally he heads off into the universe.
((ﾀﾊﾞｺ吸いに行くんだよ))
To smoke some cigarettes!
＜ しかし たどりついた
ﾊﾒｯｸ星は ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞによって➡
However, when he arrives
on Planet Hamek,
he finds it was turned into a
scorched field by Breeza.
焼け野原へと
変えられていたのであった…＞
♪♪～
Da...Dad!
((父ちゃん… 父ちゃん!!))
Dad!
＜少年 ﾃﾞﾙﾃﾞの涙｡
The young boy Delde's tears...
Hijikata channels his anger into power
and he heads toward the final battle.
怒りを力に変えて
土方は 今 最後の戦いに赴く…＞
(土方)おいっ つ～か
何で いきなり前話回想!?
Hey! Why am I suddenly having flashbacks
of the previous episode?
『ﾄﾞﾗｺﾞﾝ…』じゃねえんだからよ！
長えんだよ!!
This isn't Dragon BLEEP!
It's taking too long! I'm in a hurry!
Let's get to the main episode now!
っていうか ｵﾚは急いでるんだよ
もう 本編いくからな!!
ｸｸｸ… よもや
この私に 挑んでこようとは…｡
I never suspected that
you were against me.
その無謀さだけは評価しましょう｡
But I admire your rashness.
しかし 私の
このﾊﾟﾜｰを目の前にしても➡
But when you see my power, I wonder
if you'll still have the same attitude.
そんな態度が とれるでしょうか？
では 見せて差しあげましょう
この私のﾌﾙﾊﾟﾜｰを…！
Well, I'll show you.
My full power!
♪♪～
ｸｸｸ… ｸｸｸ…｡
どうですか？ 恐怖に
声も あげられないようですね…｡
How about that? You look like
you're scared speechless.
♪♪～
覚悟は よろしいですね？
では いきますよ！
Get ready for it.
Here I come.
♪♪～
(土方)おら ﾀﾊﾞｺ出せ
ﾃﾒｴ 持ってるんだろ｡
Hey, give me a cigarette.
I know you have some.
You destroyed Planet Hamek,
didn't you? Where are they?
ﾊﾒｯｸ星 やったんだろう どこだｺﾗ｡
ｸﾞ… このﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞ様が
こんな ｴﾃ公にやられるとは…｡
I, Breeza-sama, was knocked down
by a monkey like you.
[Note: Parody of Super Saiyan from Dragon Ball.]
It can't be...you're a legendary
Super Earthling.
まさか ｷｻﾏ 伝説のｽｰﾊﾟｰ地球人…｡
(土方)うるさいんだよ
いいから ﾀﾊﾞｺ出せ｡
Shut up, already. Just
give me a cigarette.
I'm grumpy now thanks
to nicotine withdraw.
ｲﾗｲﾗしてるんだよ ﾆｺﾁﾝ切れて…｡
ｲﾗｲﾗによって目覚めた
ｽｰﾊﾟｰ地球人…｡
You're the Super Earthling
who woke up irritated.
Don't tell me you're the
son of that Earthling
まさか ｷｻﾏ
あのとき たった１人で➡
私に挑んできた 地球人の息子…｡
who was the only one to
challenge me back then?
(土方)いや ﾀﾞﾚだよ これ…
全然 似てねえだろう！
Huh, who's this? I don't
look nothing like him.
さっきから間違えまくってるから｡
You're totally wrong.
Can it be that you're searching
for the same thing I was?
まさか ｷｻﾏも
私と同じものを探していたとは…｡
Huh?
あぁ？
(ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞ)まぁ いい｡
Whatever. I praise you for defeating me,
宇宙の帝王たる 私を倒したことを
称え くれてやろう…｡
the emperor of the universe,
so I will give you this.
Here, take it.
ほら 受け取れ…｡
(土方)全然 違うんだけど！
That's not what I asked for!
I said, give me some cigarettes!
ﾀﾊﾞｺよこせって言ったんだよ！
なんだよ このｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙのﾎﾞｰﾙ!!
What's this ball? It's so disgusting!
気持わるっ！
(ﾌﾞﾘｰｻﾞ)それは ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙﾎﾞｰﾙ｡
It's an Ooey-gooey ball.
[Note: Parody of Dragon Ball from Dragon Ball.]
７つ集めると ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙの龍が現れ
何でも 欲しい物を➡
When you collect all seven of those balls,
the Ooey-gooey dragon will appear
and make everything you want
turn Ooey-gooey.
ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙにしてくれる 不思議なﾎﾞｰﾙだ｡
It's a really mysterious ball.
(土方)何で ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙなんだよ
ほとんと 嫌がらせだろうが!!
Why Ooey-gooey? I think
you're lying to me!
欲しい物があるなら
残り６つの ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙﾎﾞｰﾙを集めて➡
If there's anything you
want but can't find,
you should collect six more balls
and have your wishes granted.
願いを叶えてもうんだな｡
おいっ！ なに その
ﾗｽ前に見せ場もらって➡
Hey! Why are you making that kind
of face made by the super villain
死んでいく 超人気敵ｷｬﾗな顔！
right before he dies in the big scene
at the end of the episode?
Anyway, why do I have to do all
of this just to get a cigarette?!
つうか ﾀﾊﾞｺ１つのために➡
どこまで 面倒くせえことしなきゃ
ならないんだよ！
冗談じゃねえぞ
どこか 適当な星に行って➡
Give me a break.
It'll be a lot faster if I just
go to another planet
自販機でﾀﾊﾞｺ買ったほうが
絶対 早い｡
and buy a pack of cigarettes
at a vending machine.
そうだ 最初から そうすりゃ
よかったんだ そうしよう｡
That's right. I should've done
that earlier. I'll go do that.
(小林)ｸﾞｯ ｸﾞｯ…｡
Grillin! Open your eyes, Grillin!
[Note: Parody of Krillin & Goku from Dragon Ball.]
ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝ…！ 目を開けろよ!! ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝ…｡
(小林)
ｸｿｯ ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙﾎﾞｰﾙさえあれば…！
Damn it! If only I had
all the Ooey-gooey balls!
Grillin!
(小林)ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝ！
ねぇ 何やってるんですか？ ｱﾝﾀ｡
...Hey, what are you doing?
I'm trying to revive Grillin.
ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝを生き返らせるんだよ｡
Who the heck is Grillin?!
(客)ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝって誰だよ いったい！
ﾀﾊﾞｺ吸いに行ったんでしょう ｱﾝﾀ｡
You came to smoke some
cigarettes, right?
(客)つうか 隣の誰!?
(小林)
おっす！ ｵﾗ 小林 ﾜｸﾜｸすっぞ!!
And who's that sitting right next to you?!
Yo! I'm Kobayashi! I'm so excited!
[Note: Parody of Goku and
Yamcha from Dragon Ball.]
(客)小林!? 全然 ﾜｸﾜｸしねえよ!!
そんな 名前｡
Kobayashi?! I'm not excited
about that name at all!
つうか ﾌﾞﾙﾏの元ｶﾚだろう それ！
You're Bulma's ex-boyfriend,
aren't you?
[Note: Refers to Bulma from Dragon Ball.
She dated Yamcha in the series.]
(土方)うるせえんだよ ｵﾒｴは！
もしかしたら お前➡
Shut up!
You know, Grillin might
have some cigarettes!
ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝが ﾀﾊﾞｺ
持ってるかもしれねえだろうが！
I'll definitely smoke next time, damn it!
次こそ 絶対
吸ってやるんだよ ﾁｸｼｮｳ！
(ｾﾛ)私がｾﾛである！ ｸﾞｱｯ…!!
I'm Celo!
[Note: Parody of Cell from Dragon Ball.]
That's enough! You're so persistent.
もう いいよ しつけえんだよ！
どうせ 長いんだろう｡
I know it's going to take a long time.
飽きるわ おら ﾎﾞｰﾙ出せ
ﾃﾒｴ 持ってるんだろ｡
I get bored easy. Hey, just give me
some balls. You have some, right?
ｸﾞｯ ｸﾞｯ… なぜだ…
どこに そんなﾊﾟﾜｰが…｡
Why? Why does he have
so much power?
(土方)うるせえよ 早くﾎﾞｰﾙ出せよ｡
Shut up!
Hurry up and give me some balls so I can
revive Grillin and smoke a cigarette.
ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝ 生き返らせて
ﾀﾊﾞｺ吸うんだよ！
ｽｰﾊﾟｰ地球人の細胞を取り込んだ
この私が負けるとは…｡
I can't believe I lost after taking
cells from the Super Earthling...
(ｽｰﾊﾟｰ地球人)はっとな！
(土方)だから 誰だよ！
Who is this guy? What's with the
scouter rip-off? It pisses me off!
[Note: Parody of the scouter device from Dragon Ball.]
何だよ そのｽｶｳﾀｰのﾊﾟﾁﾓﾝはよ！
腹立つんだよ!!
(ｾﾛ)あらゆる細胞を取り込み
ﾊﾟﾜｰｱｯﾌﾟした超完全体である➡
You defeated me, the perfect form, after
I took in every cell and powered up.
この私を倒すとは…
ｷｻﾏの攻撃は評価に値する｡
Your attack deserves to be rewarded.
As you wish, I'll give you my balls.
願いどおり ﾎﾞｰﾙはやろう…｡
ｳｯ… ｳｩ…｡
(ｾﾛ)受け取れ｡
Take these.
You hid these in there?!
They're disgusting and dirty!
どこに 隠し持ってんだ！
気持悪い上に 汚ねえだろうが!!
このﾎﾞｰﾙを使って
龍を呼び出し 私の代わりに➡
Use these balls to summon the dragon
and make a wish for me.
願いを叶えてくれたまえ｡
私の願いは ｢童貞卒業｣！
My wish is
"To graduate from being a virgin..."
何で お前の願いを
叶えるみたいな話になってんの！
Why are you making it sound like
I'm helping you grant your wish?!
And why did you make
such a useless wish?!
しかも なんちゅう しょうもない
願いを叶えようとしてたんだよ！
とにかく これでﾎﾞｰﾙが７つ揃った｡
Anyway, now that I've collected
all seven balls.
Hurry up and revive Grillin
so I can smoke a cigarette!
さっさと ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝ生き返らせて
ﾀﾊﾞｺを吸おう！
What's this? Can I eat this?
なんだこれ 食えっかな？
There's no way you can eat that disgusting
thing! What about Grillin?
(土方)そんな気持の悪いもん
食えるわけねえだろ！
(土方)ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝのことはどうした!!
(小林)あぁ そうか｡
Oh, that's right!
(土方)さっさと 龍呼び出して
ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝ 生き返らせるぞ!!
Hurry up and summon the dragon
so it can revive Grillin!
(土方/小林)いでよ ｽﾞﾙｽﾞ龍｡
我が願い 叶えたまえ｡
Come out Ooey-gooey Dragon!
Please make my wish come true!
あれ？
...Huh?
何にも起こんねえぞ｡
Nothing happened. There're seven
balls all together. What's going on?
ﾎﾞｰﾙ ７つ揃えたのに
どういうことだ？
Oh? Taking a closer look, this one
isn't an Ooey-gooey ball at all!
(小林)あり？
よく見たらこれ➡
ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙﾎﾞｰﾙじゃねえ！
なにっ!?
What?
(小林)他の６つは
正真正銘 ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙﾎﾞｰﾙだ｡
The other six balls are real Ooey-gooey
balls. But this one is...
(小林)でも これは…｡
ﾇﾙﾇﾙﾎﾞｰﾙだ！
ほとんど同じだろうが!!
...a Sticky-icky ball!
It's pretty much the same!
What's the difference between
that and an Ooey-gooey ball?!
(土方)ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙと
何が違うってんだよ!!
Yo. It's a Sticky-icky ball!
(小林)おっす｡ ﾇﾙﾇﾙすっぞ!!
That's just a technicality!
(土方)お前の感じ方の
問題だろうが!!
ほら見ろ
なんやかんやで出た!!
See?! Something is coming out!
They're all Ooey-gooey balls, after all.
(土方)やっぱり 全部
ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙﾎﾞｰﾙだったんだよ｡
(ﾇﾒﾛﾝ)よくぞ
ﾇﾒﾇﾒﾎﾞｰﾙを集めたな｡
Great job in collecting all
the Slimy-grimy balls.
(土方)ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙでも ﾇﾙﾇﾙでも
ないんですけど！
It's not Ooey-gooey, nor Sticky-icky!
That's the least of our problems.
Hey, hurry up and save Grillin.
もう この際
何でもいいや｡
ほら 早くｸﾞﾘﾘﾝを｡
I see. It's not Ooey-gooey.
Then I don't care.
なんだ ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙじゃねえのか
じゃ ｵﾗいいや｡
なんでだ！ ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙにどんだけ
こだわりがあるんだよ！
Why?! How much loyalty do
you have for Ooey-gooey?!
どんだけ ｸﾞﾘﾘﾝを
ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙにしたいんだ ﾃﾒｪは！
How badly do you want to
make Grillin Ooey-gooey?!
Just ask him! It doesn't matter
if he's Slimy-grimy!
(土方)いいから 頼めって｡
別に ﾇﾒﾇﾒでもいいだろうが｡
仲間なんだろ！
He's your friend, right?
If it's Slimy-grimy, I prefer
something else.
(小林)ﾇﾒﾇﾒなら ｵﾗ 他のがいい｡
(土方)他のって何だよ｡
What do you mean, something else?
ｷﾞｬﾙのﾊﾟﾝﾁｰ おくれ!!
おい!!
Give me some gal's panties!
[Note: A famous line from Dragon Ball when they
first met Shen Long, the dragon.]
Hey!
ﾇﾒﾇﾒのｷﾞｬﾙのﾊﾟﾝﾁｰって お前➡
A gal's Slimy-grimy panties?!
どんだけ生々しいの
注文してんだ！
That's such a gross wish!
Don't request a pair of dirty panties
and give up your friend!
仲間 見捨てて
汚ねえﾊﾟﾝﾂ 選んでんじゃねえよ！
なし｡ 今のなしな｡
Never mind! Forget it!
Hurry up. Or the Slimy-grimy will dry up.
早くしろ
ﾇﾒﾇﾒが乾いてしまうだろうが｡
Wait! Hold on a second!
(土方)待て ちょっと待て｡
ﾇﾒﾇﾒのﾀﾊﾞｺなんてもらっても
吸えねえ｡
If I have a Slimy-grimy cigarette,
I can't smoke it.
What should I wish for?
何を頼めば…｡
I'm about to dry up!
乾いてしまう｡
あっ そうだ｡
I know!
(土方)
最高の１本を手に入れよう｡
I'll get the last one.
(長老)あなたは…｡
You're...
(長老)なぜ またここに？
Why are you here again?
I've changed my mind...
I want the last cigarette.
やっぱり あの最後の１本のﾀﾊﾞｺ
もらおうと思ってな｡
I know that's an important memento
from your dad. But...
(土方)わかってるさ
親父の大事な形見ってことは｡
(土方)だが…｡
形見なんて
もう 必要ねえだろ｡
...you don't need a memento anymore
if you have your dad back.
親父がいれば｡
まさか… と…｡
Don't tell me... Da...
(父)ﾇﾒﾇﾒ～｡
あぁ 父ちゃんだ｡
Yeah. It's your dad.
Whose dad is he?!
(ﾃﾞﾙﾃﾞ)どこが父ちゃんだ！
なんだ このｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙ！
What's with this Ooey-gooey?!
(土方)いや ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙじゃなくて ﾇﾒﾇﾒ｡
No, it's not Ooey-gooey, it's Slimy-grimy!
There's a limit to disgracing the dead!
(長老)死者を冒涜するにも
ほどがあるじゃろう！
(土方)いや ﾎﾝﾄなんだって｡
ﾇﾒﾇﾒなんだけど これ本物｡
No, it's true. Even if it's
Slimy-grimy, he's real...
また ｱﾝﾀですか
ﾀﾊﾞｺ吸えました？
It's you again.
Were you able to smoke
a cigarette, after all?
次は どこ行くんですか？
Where will you go next?
(土方)ﾌｯ… ｵﾚ決めたよ｡
I've decided...
ﾀﾊﾞｺ やめる｡
...to quit smoking.
After Hijikata returned to earth,
he wasn't able to give
up smoking, after all.
In order to get the legendary cigarette,
Hijikata works hard at training.
And a new powerful enemy appears before him.
Next episode will be Ooey-gooey
ball, episode 120.
Cut it out! This can't be right!
Everyone! Please watch it!
[Note: Parody of next week
remark from Dragon Ball.]
I said, shut up!
[Preview]
Oh, good for you, Hasegawa-san.
I heard you'll head up the conveyor belt sushi
restaurant all by yourself, after all.
The next episode... "Once you've chosen
a dish, you can't give it back."
Have some sushi!
[Actually, there'll be two episodes next week. The other episode... "Japanese Restaurants Abroad Taste Pretty Much like School Cafeteria Lunches"]
[The plan is to sneak into an Amanto restaurant,
but for some reason, Prince Hata was working there.]
[See you next time.]
♪♪～
＜ｶﾞﾒ仙人:地球に戻った土方は
結局➡
ﾀﾊﾞｺをやめることができなかった｡
伝説のﾀﾊﾞｺを得るために➡
修業に明け暮れる
土方たちの前に また➡
新たな強敵が立ちふさがる｡
次回 ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙﾎﾞｰﾙ 第120話＞
(土方)しつけえんだよ！
やってたまるか！
(小林)みんな 絶対見てくれよな！
(土方)だから黙れ！